sunysb.edu 2005-12-31

# Stony Brook University Privacy Policy

COMMITMENT TO PRIVACY  
At the Stony Brook University, we are committed to protecting your privacy and making it easier and more efficient for individuals and businesses to interact with the University. We recognize that it is critical for individuals and businesses to be confident that their privacy is protected when they visit this Web site. You can travel through most of this Web site without giving us any information about yourself. Sometimes we do need information to provide services that you request, and this commitment of privacy explains our online information practices. 

Stony Brook University does not collect any _personal information_ about you unless you provide that information voluntarily by sending an e-mail, completing an Information Request Form, or completing the online application. 

This policy is consistent with the provisions of the Internet Security and Privacy Act, the Freedom of Information Law, and the Personal Privacy Protection Law. 

Information Collected Automatically When You Visit this Web Site  
When you visit this Web site, the University automatically collects and stores the following information about your visit: 

  * The Internet Protocol address of the computer that accessed this Web site 
  * The type of browser, its version, and the operating system on which that browser is running
  * The Web page from which the _user_ accessed the current Web page
  * The date and time of the _user's_ request
  * The pages that were visited and the amount of time spent at each page 

None of the above-mentioned information is deemed to constitute _personal information_ by the [Internet Privacy and Security Act](http://assembly.state.ny.us/leg/?cl=114&a=3). The information that is collected automatically is used to improve the content of this Web site and to help Stony Brook University understand how _users_ are interacting with its Web site. This information is collected for statistical analysis and to determine what information is of most and least interest to our _users_. The information is not collected for commercial marketing purposes and Stony Brook University is not authorized to sell or otherwise disclose the information collected from this Web site for commercial marketing purposes. 

Information Collected When You E-Mail the University or Complete a Transaction   
During your visit to this Web site you may send an e-mail to the University. Your e-mail address and the contents of your message will be collected. The information collected is not limited to text characters and may include audio, video, and graphic information formats included in the message. Your e-mail address and the information included in your message will be used to respond to you, to address issues you identify, to improve this Web site, or to forward your message to the appropriate campus office for response. Your e-mail address is not collected for commercial purposes and Stony Brook University is not authorized to sell or otherwise disclose your e-mail address for commercial purposes. 

During your visit to this Web site you may complete a transaction such as an online application or an Information Request Form. The information collected by the University, including _personal information_ volunteered by you in completing the transaction, is used by Stony Brook University and may be disclosed to other parties for those purposes that may be reasonably ascertained from the nature and terms of the transaction in which the information was submitted. 

Stony Brook University does not knowingly collect _personal information_ from children under the age of 13 or create profiles of children under the age of 13. _Users_ are cautioned, however, that the collection of _personal information_ submitted in an e-mail will be treated as though it were submitted by an adult, and may, unless exempted from access by federal or State law, be subject to public access. 

Disclosure of Information Collected Through this Web Site   
The collection of information through this Web site and the disclosure of that information are subject to the provisions of the Internet Security and Privacy Act. Stony Brook University will only collect _personal information_ through this Web site or disclose _personal information_ collected through this Web site if the _user_ has consented to the collection or disclosure of such _personal information_. The voluntary disclosure of _personal information_ to Stony Brook University by the _user_ , constitutes consent to the collection and disclosure of the information by Stony Brook University for the purposes for which the _user_ disclosed the information to Stony Brook University. 

However, Stony Brook University may collect or disclose _personal information_ without consent if the collection or disclosure is: (1) necessary to perform the statutory duties of Stony Brook University, or necessary for Stony Brook University to operate a program authorized by law, or authorized by state or federal statute or regulation; (2) made pursuant to a court order or by law; (3) for the purpose of validating the identity of the _user_ ; or (4) of information to be used solely for statistical purposes that is in a form that cannot be used to identify any particular person. 

Further, the disclosure of information, including _personal information_ , collected through this Web site is subject to the provisions of the Freedom of Information Law and the Personal Privacy Protection Law.  
Stony Brook University may disclose _personal information_ to federal or state law enforcement authorities to enforce its rights against unauthorized access or attempted unauthorized access to Stony Brook University’s information technology assets. 

Retention of Information Collected Through this Web Site  
The information collected through this Web site is retained by Stony Brook University in accordance with the records retention and disposition requirements of the New York State Arts & Cultural Affairs Law. Information on the requirements of the Arts & Cultural Affairs Law may be found at <http://www.archives.nysed.gov/services/recmgmt.htm>. In general, the Internet services logs of Stony Brook University, comprising electronic files or automated logs created to monitor access and use of Agency services provided through this Web site, are retained for 21 business days and then destroyed. Information concerning these records retention and disposition schedules may be obtained through the Internet privacy policy contact listed in this policy. 

Access to and Correction of _Personal Information_ Collected Through this Web Site  
Any _user_ may submit a request to Stony Brook University's privacy compliance officer to determine whether _personal information_ pertaining to that _user_ has been collected through Stony Brook University. Any such request shall be made in writing and must be accompanied by reasonable proof of identity of the _user_. Reasonable proof of identity may include verification of a signature, inclusion of an identifier generally known only to the _user_ , or similar appropriate identification. The address of the privacy compliance officer is: 

> Office of University Counsel  
>  State University of New York at Stony Brook  
>  Administration Room 328  
>  Stony Brook, New York 11794

The privacy compliance officer shall, within five (5) business days of the receipt of a proper request, provide access to the _personal information_ ; deny access in writing, explaining the reasons therefor; or acknowledge the receipt of the request in writing, stating the approximate date when the request will be granted or denied, which date shall not be more than thirty (30) days from the date of the acknowledgment. 

In the event that Stony Brook University has collected _personal information_ pertaining to a _user_ through this Web site and that information is to be provided to the _user_ pursuant to the _user_ ’s request, the privacy compliance officer shall inform the _user_ of his or her right to request that the _personal information_ be amended or corrected under the procedures set forth in [section 95 of the Public Officers Law](http://www.tenant.net/Other_Laws/Pubofc/pubofc08.txt). 

Confidentiality and Integrity of _Personal Information_ Collected Through this Web Site  
Stony Brook University is strongly committed to protecting _personal information_ collected through this Web site against unauthorized access, use, or disclosure. Consequently, Stony Brook University limits employee access to _personal information_ collected through this Web site to only those employees who need access to the information in the performance of their official duties. Employees who have access to this information follow appropriate procedures in connection with any disclosures of _personal information_. 

In addition, Stony Brook University has implemented procedures to safeguard the integrity of its information technology assets, including, but not limited to, authentication, authorization, monitoring, auditing, and encryption. These security procedures have been integrated into the design, implementation, and day-to-day operations of this Web site as part of our continuing commitment to the security of electronic content as well as the electronic transmission of information. 

For Web site security purposes and to maintain the availability of this Web site for all _users_ , Stony Brook University employs software to monitor traffic to identify unauthorized attempts to upload or change information or otherwise damage this Web site. 

Cookies  
Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored by the _user_ 's browser on the hard drive of the _user_ 's computer. This Web site uses cookies for some of its applications. 

Disclaimer  
The information provided in this privacy policy should not be construed as giving business, legal, or other advice, or warranting as failproof, the security of information provided through this Web site. 

Contact Information   
For questions regarding this Internet privacy policy, please contact our privacy officer via e-mail at [privacy@stonybrook.edu](mailto:privacy@stonybrook.edu) or by regular mail at: 

> Office of University Counsel  
>  State University of New York at Stony Brook  
>  Administration Room 328  
>  Stony Brook, New York 11794 

Definitions  
The following definitions apply to, and appear in italics, in this policy: 

_Personal information:_ For purposes of this policy, “ _personal information_ ” means any information concerning a natural person which, because of name, number, symbol, mark, or other identifier, can be used to identify that natural person. 

_User_ shall have the meaning set forth in subdivision 8 of section 202 of the State Technology Law. 

* * *

[SB Home](http://www.stonybrook.edu/sb/index.shtml) |[ Welcome Center](http://www.stonybrook.edu/sb/welcome.shtml) | [Admissions](http://www.stonybrook.edu/sb/admissions.shtml) | [Academics](http://www.stonybrook.edu/sb/academics.shtml) | [Research](http://www.stonybrook.edu/sb/research.shtml) [  
Faculty and Staff](http://www.stonybrook.edu/sb/faculty.shtml) | [Athletics](http://www.goseawolves.org/) | [For Students](http://www.stonybrook.edu/sb/studentlife.shtml) | [ In the Greater Community](http://www.stonybrook.edu/sb/community/) [  
Hospital and Health Care](http://www.stonybrook.edu/sb/hospital.shtml)
